我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
by something impossible.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
妈妈
Mom!
让我父亲沉冤得雪
And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
那晚我们在力场困住了逆闪电
The night we trapped The Reverse-Flash in the force field,
囚禁系统没理由会失败的
there's no reason that the containment system should have failed.
我一直在做同一个梦
I've been having these dreams.
梦里都发生了什么事
What happens in the dream?
威尔斯博士就是逆闪电
Dr. Wells is The Reverse-Flash,
而且他还杀了我
and he kills me.
如果这是威尔斯博士
If this is Dr. Wells,
那一直和我们合作的人是谁
then who have we been working for this whole time?
根本就是另外一个人
A completely different person.
天呐
Oh, my God.
搞什么啊
What the frack?
闪电侠失踪  消失于危机之中
"Flash missing. Vanishes in crisis."
在与逆闪电进行了一场大战之后
"After an epic street battle with The Reverse-Flash,
属于我们城市的红色极速者
"our city's very own Scarlet Speedster
消失在强光之中
disappeared in an explosion of light."
巴里  你看日期
Barry, look at the date.
2024年  四月二十五日
April 25th, 2024.
伙计们  当我圣诞节和逆闪电打斗时
Guys, when I fought The Reverse-Flash at Christmas,
他说我们会争斗数个世纪
he said that we'd be fighting for centuries.
等下  你不会真的认为这报道是属于...
Wait, you can't really think that this is from...
未来的
the future.
那就是说威尔斯博士  不管他是谁  也是
That would means Dr. Wells, or whoever he is, is also...
属于未来的
From the future.
不过要我说  我真的挺喜欢
I have to say, I'm really digging
这更亮红一些的衣服
the brighter red suit.
而且标志上边的白色
And the white on the symbol?
挺酷的
That's dope.
等一下
Wait a second.
如果说我们改变了你衣服的颜色
Suppose we now change the color on your suit.
会不会是因为我们从这照片中获得的启发
Will it be because we got the idea from this picture?
这也就是处在因果关系之中了
That would mean we're living in a causal nexus.
这个  这可真是让人迷糊
This--wow. This is so trippy.
像是  马蒂和宝丽来那种迷糊
Like, Marty and the Polaroid trippy.
最让人迷糊的还是署名栏
Not as trippy as the name on the byline.
作者 爱瑞丝·韦斯特艾伦
爱瑞丝·韦斯特艾伦
Iris West-Allen?
恭喜你
Mazel tov?
希伯来语
Hebrew.
犹太人的古语
Ancient language of the Jewish people.
那是什么玩意
What the hell was that?
有人在这里吗
Is someone here?
你好
Hello?
晚上好  巴里·艾伦
Good evening, Barry Allen.
-你知道我是谁  -当然
- You know who I am? - Of course.
巴里·艾伦  中城警局主管
Barry Allen, director of Central City Police,
犯罪现场调查科
CSI Division.
主管
Director?
我想你是升职了
I guess you get a promotion.
同时也是闪电侠
Also known as The Flash.
与其他成员一同创建了...
Founding member of--
你是谁
What are you?
我是吉迪恩
I am Gideon,
交互式人工意识
an interactive artificial consciousness.
人工智能
AI.
棒啊
Sick.
你认识威尔斯博士吗
You know Dr. Wells?
是的
Yes.
你知道他真正的身份吗
Do you know who he really is?
我不理解这个问题
I don't understand the question.
我是说  他在这干什么
I...I mean, what is he doing here?
他为什么要来这里
W-why did he come here?
为了杀死你
To kill you.
威尔斯进大楼了
Wells is in the building.
什么  你怎么知道的
What? How do you know that?
我在他轮椅上放了追踪器
I put a tracker on his wheelchair.
如果我们错怪了他  他真的瘫痪了
Which, if we're wrong about him and he is paralyzed,
我就要遭天谴了
I'm going to hell for that one.
他在表层控制室  快问问题
He's in the Cortex. Ask questions fast.
他为什么要杀死诺拉·艾伦
Why did he kill Nora Allen?
因为他很愤怒
Because he was angry.
怒什么
About what?
因为你逃跑了
That you escaped.
他在B层了  他正往这里赶来
He's on B level. He's coming this way.
他想从我这里得到什么
What does he want from me?
让你变成闪电侠
For you to be The Flash.
也许这就是为什么威尔斯让粒子加速器爆炸
Maybe that's why Wells let the particle accelerator explode,
这样你就可以成为闪电侠了
so that you could become The Flash.
为什么  我是说  这有什么好处
Why? I mean, for what reason?
伙计们  咱们得走了  他快到了
Guys, we got to go. He's almost here.
-快点  - 好吧
- Hurry. - All right.
等一下  等等
Wait a second. Wait.
如果这全息人告诉威尔斯我们来过怎么办
What if HAL over there tells Wells that we were in here?
那就太糟糕了
That would be bad.
如果我能进入它的操作系统
If I can get into its operating system,
也许我能禁用记忆核心
maybe I can disable its memory core.
吉迪恩  能告诉我们你的操作系统在哪吗
Gideon, can you show us where your operating system is?
没问题
Certainly.
好吧  没戏
Yeah. Nope.
这根本不可能
That's not gonna happen.
伙计们  他在走廊里了
Guys, he's in the corridor.
吉迪恩  你能不能  就
Gideon, could you just, like,
别告诉他我们来过
not tell him that we were here?
当然可以
Of course.
我会接受任何你给予我的命令
I will accept any command given to me by you.
-巴里  -快点
- Barry. - Come on.
-咱们得离开这里了  -等等
- We got to get out of here. - Wait, wait, wait.
为什么你会接受我的命令
Why would you accept my commands?
因为是你创造的我
Because you created me.
晚上好  吉迪恩
Good evening, Gideon.
晚上好  威尔斯博士
Good evening, Dr. Wells.
一切都正常吗
Is everything all right?
一切都正常
Everything is fine.
闪电侠
第一季  第二十集
有什么急事
What's the emergency?
没什么急事
Oh, no emergency.
我只是想
I just wanted to, you know,
和你谈谈
talk to you...
谢谢
Thanks.
不带爱瑞丝
Without Iris around
也没有巴里
or Barry around
或是西斯科  或是凯瑟琳
or Cisco around or Caitlin around.
所以换句话说就是  你想和我单独谈谈
So, in other words, you want to talk to me alone.
是什么事
What is it?
好吧
Right.
听我说
So listen.
所有发生的这一切
With everything going on--
调查威尔斯  知道巴里的身份
investigating Wells and finding out about Barry--
艾迪  你不能告诉爱瑞丝巴里的事
Eddie, you cannot tell Iris about Barry.
这不是关于巴里的
This isn't about Barry.
我知道这时机可能不太对
I know the timing might seem off, you know,
发生了这么多事
with everything that's going on,
但是  我想向爱瑞丝求婚
but I want to propose to Iris,
我希望能获得你的祝福
and I'd like your blessing.
不行
No.
你说什么
Come again?
不行
No.
我不会祝福你们
You do not have my blessing.
是巴里  咱们得走了
That's Barry. We got to go.
乔  我只是礼节性地问你的意见
Joe, I only asked as a courtesy,
出于对你的尊敬
out of respect.
我不需要你的许可
I don't need your permission.
真的假的啊
Really?
对于三个非常聪明的人来说
For three very smart people,
这事可办的够蠢的
that was really stupid.
如果你们被威尔斯逮个正着在那什么
What if Wells had caught you in that...
-时间穹顶  -谢谢
- Time vault. - Thank you.
好吧  我知道我们今年见识了不少事情
Okay, I know we've seen a lot this past year,
但是时间旅行
but time travel?
我做到了
I did it.
-或者说我以后会做到  -什么
- Or I will do it, I mean. - Excuse me?
巴里母亲去世的那晚
One of the two speedsters in Barry's house
他家里出现的两个极速者之一是巴里
the night his mother died was Barry.
我是说  闪电侠  他在场
I mean, The Flash. He was there.
这就意味着未来的某一天
Which means that one day in the future,
巴里会时间旅行到那一晚
Barry will travel back in time to that night.
好吧
Okay.
其实  我说的不是那次
Actually, I wasn't talking about that.
我好像已经时间旅行过了
I kind of already time traveled.
-纯属意外  -什么
- By accident. - What?
我正跑去试图阻止一场
I was running to try and stop a tsunami
正要登陆中城的海啸
from hitting the city--
那是什么时候的事
When was that?
几周之前
A few weeks ago.
就在你开始做那些奇怪的梦之前
Right before you started getting those dreams.
你是指那些威尔斯
Oh, you mean the ones where Wells uses
用他极速移动的手撕碎我的心的梦吗
his super-speeding hand to shred apart my heart?
-就是那些  -对  正是
- Those? - Yes, right.
所以  如果它们不是梦呢
So, what if they're not dreams?
那它们能是什么
What else could they be?
记忆
Memories.
我不太懂
I'm not following.
好吧  如果那一天  西斯科发现
All right, what if, that day, Cisco found out
威尔斯是逆闪  然后威尔斯杀了他
that Wells is The Reverse-Flash, and then Wells killed him?
但我回到了前一天
But when I ran back a day,
改变了时间线  所以那事没有发生
I changed the timeline so that event never happened.
如果这事没发生  那西斯科怎么会记得
If it never happened, how can Cisco remember it?
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
我觉得关键是  他记得
I think the important thing is, he does.
大伙  我觉得我想到了
Guys, I think I've got
一个很糟的主意
a really bad idea.
星城出现了更多的抢劫案
爸  已经三周了你几乎不吃不睡的
Dad, it's been three weeks. You barely eat or sleep.
也许也该回趟家了
You should probably go home at some point.
-嗨  宝贝  -嗨
- Hey, baby. - Hi.
等巴里能回家了  我就回家
I'll go home when Barry does.
哦天呐  哦天呐
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
救人啊  我儿子心脏骤停了
Help! My son's coding.
他们说他的病情是稳定的
They said he was stable.
巴里
Barry.
-我的天啊  -我需要空间
- Oh, my God. - I need the room.
快走开  我需要腾出空间
Just go. I need the room.
他怎么会抽搐呢
How can he be seizing?
他已经没有心跳了啊
He has no heart rhythm.
-开始胸外按压   -注射肾上腺素
- Starting compressions. - Epi push. Epi.
他们救不了他
They can't save him.
但我可以
But I can.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你是那个巴里崇拜的科学家
You're that scientist that Barry's obsessed with,
那个把城市炸了个洞的人
the one who blew a hole in the city.
哈里森·威尔斯  有趣的是
Harrison Wells, and interestingly enough,
我的实验室正是我想把他带去的地方
my facility is the very place I would like to take him.
你疯了吧
You're out of your mind.
我不会试着用保证来说服你
I'm not gonna try and convince you with promises.
但是  警探  给我一个机会
But, Detective, give me a chance.
我觉得我们已经清楚你的能力了  教授
I think we already know what you're capable of, Doctor.
你在那晚伤害了很多人
You hurt a lot of people that night.
所以这里的医生们  他们够出色吗
So those doctors in there, they're good enough?
市里最好的医生  全国最好的
The best in the city, best in the country.
看看他们
Look at them.
他们对发生的事情毫无头绪
They have no clue what's going on.
他们被吓坏了  巴里体内
They're baffled, and the reason for that is
发生这一切的原因是个谜
what's happening inside Barry is a mystery,
而且他们没有解决问题的工具
and they don't have the tools to solve it.
-但你有  -正是如此
- But you do? - That's right.
上百万的人
Millions of people
曾参观过我的实验室  他们看到了什么
used to look at my lab, and what did they see?
看到了未来
They saw the future.
让我用那种科技
Well, let me take that technology,
让我用我的专业知识
let me take that know-how into ensuring
来保证你的儿子还能有个未来
that your son actually does have a future.
警探
Detective.
让我救他吧
Let me save him.
-把电极板递给我  -开始做胸外按压
- Hand me the paddles. - Starting compressions.
那就去救他吧
Then save him.
充电到200焦  启动电击除颤
Charge. 200. Pads.
乔
Joe?
乔  你还在听吗
Joe, are you listening?
嗯
Yeah.
我们要设法读取西斯科的记忆
We--we have to access Cisco's memories somehow.
他潜意识中某处暗藏着答案
Somewhere in his subconscious is the key.
什么的答案
The key to what now?
如何把我父亲弄出监狱
Getting my dad out of prison.
这又要怎么做到
And how are we going to do that?
我们要让威尔斯承认他杀了我母亲
We're gonna get Wells to confess to killing my mom.
所以这个可以让西斯科
So, this will allow Cisco
读取他的梦
to see into his dream?
我从杂志上的一篇文章上得到了
I got the idea from a journal article
关于清醒梦境治疗法的灵感
on lucid dream therapy.
他们认为这可以用于帮助
They think it can be used to help people
那些患创伤后应激障碍症折磨的病人
suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder.
受创伤  有压力
Traumatized, stressed?
我都中了
Check and check.
这理论就是它能让人们
The theory is that it will allow people
客观地进入梦境
to objectively enter their dreams
直面他们的恐惧
and face their fears.
我还在研究怎么让他们说话
Still working on the talking part.
你确定这东西不会
And you're sure this thing isn't gonna, you know,
影响我的大脑
mess with my brain?
激发清醒梦境状态
Oh, the amount of electricity required
所需的电量是无害人体的
to trigger lucid dreaming is harmless.
也许吧
Probably.
谁要进入清醒梦境啊
Who's going to be lucid dreaming?
中城里有这么多超能力者
With all of the meta-humans in Central City,
人们开始出现奇怪的幻觉
people have been seeing some strange things--
看到他们不理解的事物
things that they don't understand.
而且出现心理问题
And it's really just a matter of time
只是时间早晚问题
before psychological issues develop.
而清醒梦境能帮助医生们
And lucid dreaming will help the doctors
更好地理解患者的恐惧
better understand their fears.
有意思
Intriguing.
当然  你需要还是需要从外界
Of course, you still need to guide the patient
引导病人  对吗
from the outside, right?
把他们引导到梦里的具体方面
Direct them to specific aspects of the dream.
我们还在研究交流界面
We're still working on a communications interface.
当我们做梦时
When we dream,
中脑内充满了脑电活动
the middle brain lights up with electrical activity,
而高级脑保持休眠状态
whereas the higher brain remains dormant.
只要我们能让大脑这两部分都处于活跃状态
Once we find a way to make both parts of the brain active,
那问题就是找到某个频率
then it's just a matter of finding the frequency
来刺激语言中枢
that will stimulate the language center.
然后做梦者就可以说话了
Then the dreamer could speak.
他可以描述他的梦
He could describe his dream.
-正是如此  -或者她的梦
- Exactly. - Or her dream.
这可以用于任何人
It could be used for anyone.
是的  不限性别
Right, it's not gender specific.
我会先试试45赫兹的频率
I would try a frequency of 45 hertz to start.
谢谢你  威尔斯教授
Thank you, Dr. Wells.
你真是让我惊喜不断啊  凯特琳
Well, you never cease to impress me, Caitlin.
中城警局
-艾伦  -嗨
- Allen. - Hey.
欧文斯的案子
The Owens case.
我还在等你给我纤维证据
I'm still waiting on the fiber evidence
和弹道测试结果
and the ballistics report.
你是去度假了还是怎样吗
Are you on vacation or something?
没有  抱歉  我只是
No, I'm so sorry, I've just--
在忙另一个案子
I've been distracted by another case.
这不是理由  我只是
Which is no excuse, I just--
行了  等你做好把报告给我
Okay, just get me the reports when you can.
不用着急
There's -- there's no rush.
好的  队长
All right. Captain?
你没事吧
Is everything okay?
自从我和罗布开始策划
Yeah, since Rob and I have been planning the,
婚礼那些事  挑选配花啊
you know, wedding, between the florist
试尝了几百种蛋糕馅儿
and the hundreds of kinds of cake filling
安排座位
and who can sit next to who...
千万别结婚  艾伦
Never get married, Allen.
好吧
Right.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
巴里
Barry.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没  没事
Yeah. No. Yes.
只是好奇怪
That was -- that was just really weird.
见辛格队长这么温柔
Captain Singh was nice to me.
他心情好嘛
Oh, well, he's in a good mood.
马上要结婚了
He's about to get married.
他真幸运啊  我理解
Lucky him. Yeah, I know, it's...
我能跟你单独谈谈吗
Oh, hey, can I talk to you in private?
和工作有点关系
It's -- it's kind of work-related.
现在恐怕不行
Okay, yeah, now's not a great time.
-抱歉  我还有事  -你好  美女
- I'm sorry, I've got-- - Hi, beautiful.
巴里  我能跟你说两句吗
Barry, can I grab you for a second?
当然  可以
Absolutely. Yeah.
好吧  那你完事了给我打电话好吗
Okay, well, can you call me when you're done?
这事真的很重要
It's -- it's really important.
好的  好的
Yeah. Yeah.
怎么了
What's up?
好吧
Oh. O-okay.
她怎么回答的
W-what did she say?
不对  还在你这儿所以你肯定还没问吧
Or, wait, you still have it, so, duh, you haven't asked her yet.
还是说你已经问了  结果被她
Or you did ask her, and she said...
-我打算今晚求婚  -好的
- I was gonna propose tonight. - All right.
但我去找乔希望他能祝福我们
But I went to Joe to ask for his blessing.
-他说不行  -是吗  他
- He said no. - He did? He--
-而且一直说不行  -真奇怪
- Repeatedly. - Uh, weird.
我需要你帮我问问他为什么
I need you to talk to him, find out why.
艾迪
Uh, Eddie...
我知道我这么要求你
Look, I know me asking you like this,
是有点尴尬
it's a little awkward.
有点
Yeah.
但你明白如果让她知道
But you know how heartbroken she's gonna be
乔不同意她会有多伤心
if she finds out that Joe's not on board.
是啊  好吧
Yeah. Yeah, all right.
我会问问他  哥们儿
Yeah, I'll talk to him, man.
谢谢  我十分感激
Oh, thanks. I appreciate it so much.
-好的  -未来的斯旺夫人也会感激的
- Yeah. - And so will the future Mrs. Thawne.
爱瑞丝·斯旺
Iris Thawne.
很棒对吧
Sounds pretty good, huh?
有种预感她可能会在中间加个连字符
I have a feeling she's gonna want to hyphenate.
好的  再讲一遍过程好吗
Okay, can we go over this one more time?
好的  你戴上眼镜睡觉然后做梦
Yeah, you put the glasses on, fall asleep, and start dreaming.
不难吧
Not that hard.
除了我很确定我死在了梦里的部分以外
Yeah, except I'm pretty sure I die in this dream.
如果我进了梦里  结果真的死了呢
If I go back into it, am I gonna die in real life?
这到底是什么系统啊
I mean, what are we talking about here?
《盗梦空间》还是《魔域煞星》
Is this Inception or Dreamscape?
给你  喝了吧
Here. Drink this.
我又不是五岁小孩了
What, am I five?
喝吧
Just drink it.
好吧  我喝
Okay, I'll drink it.
你不会有事的  西斯科
You're gonna be fine, Cisco.
好的
Okay.
眼镜会放射低能三角波
The glasses are emitting a low-level delta wave
有助你尽快入睡
which should help you fall asleep.
好的
Okay.
我得提醒你一句
I got to warn you, though,
通常我要很长时间才能入睡
usually it takes me a long time.
就是
I mean...
我不是说我
I'm not saying I'm, like...
会失眠什么的
an insomniac or any...
原来只有睡着了他才会闭嘴
So that's how you get him to shut up.
他进入快速眼动阶段了
He's entering REM.
成功了
It's working.
西斯科
Cisco.
能听到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
你在做梦呢  哥们
You're dreaming, bud.
好的  我会带威尔斯博士去吉特斯
Okay, I will take Dr. Wells to Jitters
你想干什么就去吧
so you do whatever it is you want to do.
各位  这太诡异了
Guys, this is mad freaky.
好的
Okay,
你在哪里
where are you?
在表层
In the Cortex.
我知道我是梦见我在表层
I mean, I know I'm just dreaming that I'm in the Cortex,
但感觉好真实
but it feels so real.
梦里的你在干什么
What is dream you doing?
凯特琳刚走
Caitlin just left.
我让她带威尔斯去吉特斯
I asked her to take Wells to Jitters.
你为什么要把威尔斯弄出实验室
Why--why do you want Wells out of the lab?
我觉得他会影响我的工作
I think he might have tampered with my work.
我要去检查
I need to check.
好的
Okay.
好的  我正在向地堡走去
Okay, I'm walking to the bunker.
哥们  我好喜欢这件衣服的
Oh, man, I love this shirt.
我还以为是丢在烘干机里了呢
I thought the dryer ate it.
专心点  西斯科
Focus, Cisco.
好好
Okay, okay.
好的
All right.
现在我在检测牢房系统
Now I'm running tests on the containment system.
这个数据  有点不对劲
This data -- it doesn't make any sense.
所有超级电容器
All the supercapacitors--
都在正常工作
they were all still fully charged.
黄衣人完全不可能
There's absolutely no reason that The Man in Yellow
逃脱的
should have escaped.
天呐
Oh, my God.
那只是个全息图
It was just a hologram.
他骗了我们
He tricked us.
你好  西斯科
Hello, Cisco.
天呐  威尔斯来了
Oh, God, Wells is here.
西斯科  这只是梦  他伤害不到你的
Cisco, it's just a dream. He can't hurt you.
你说的最好是对的
You better be right about that.
我叫艾尔伯德·斯旺
My name is Eobard Thawne.
艾尔伯德·斯旺
Eobard Thawne.
斯旺  和艾迪同姓吗
Thawne? Like Eddie Thawne?
你杀了诺拉·艾伦
You killed Nora Allen.
那并非我的本意
It was never my intention.
诺拉  我妈妈怎么了
Nora? What about my mom?
他承认了
He's confessing.
西斯科
Cisco?
他  他并不想杀她
He -- he didn't want to kill her.
是你  巴里
It was you, Barry.
他是想去杀你
He was trying to kill you.
他的血压已经200了  心跳147
His blood pressure's 200 and his heart rate is 147.
高级神经机能在停止作用
Guys, he's losing higher brain function.
西斯科  你不会有事的
Cisco, you're gonna be okay.
这只是个梦  你不会有事的
It's just a dream. You're gonna be okay.
我已经有点喜欢上你了  西斯科
I have grown quite fond of you, Cisco.
他的手  在振动
His hand-- it's vibrating.
他要杀我了
He's gonna kill me!
天呐  他会中风的
Oh, God. He's gonna have a stroke.
叫醒他
Get him out of there!
从很多方面
In many ways,
你带给了我一种
you've shown me what it's like...
救我
Help me.
快救救我
Help me, please!
有儿子的感觉
to have a son.
救我
Help me!
你没事
You're okay.
只是做梦而已  你没事
It was just a dream. You're okay.
天呐
Oh God.
感觉好真实
It felt so real.
-巴里  -我妈妈
- Barry? - My mom.
真的是我的错
This was my fault.
你好
Hello?
你在哪
Where are you?
巴里
Barry.
巴里  你在听吗
Barry, are you there?
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells.
在  抱歉  在听
Yeah. It's--sorry, yeah.
这儿信号不好
It's--it's a bad connection right now.
你去哪了
Where have you been?
我们在  怎么了  出什么事了
Uh, we're-- Why? What's going on?
火灾
A fire.
刚发生了一起超大火灾
A huge fire just erupted.
火灾  在哪
A fire? Where?
新布莱顿
New Brighton.
布拉德福德大厦高层
Bradford Tower High-Rise.
我知道那栋大厦
I know that building.
辛格队长的未婚夫在那上班
That's where Captain Singh's fiance works.
马上去
On my way.
赶快行动  快
Now move it! Go!
立起水管  快点
Get those hoses up. Move!
告诉调度中心有多少消防车就派多少过来
And tell dispatch we need as many tankers as this city has.
-哪一层楼  -二十一
- What floor? - 21st.
天呐  罗布在那上班
God. That's where Rob works.
拜托快点
Please hurry.
这里
Over here!
威尔斯博士  洒水装置
Dr. Wells, the sprinklers--
不能用
they're not working.
我知道了
I see that.
把所有人都救出去就行  巴里
Just get everyone out of there, Barry.
不  我不行  我不可能救得了所有人
No, I can't. I can't save them all.
威尔斯博士  拜托了  我要怎么做
Dr. Wells, please, what do I do?
你造出一台真空机
You create a vacuum.
超速度转动你的手臂
Rotate your arms at super-speed.
就会创造出一个导风漏斗
That'll create a wind funnel
能把房间里的空气都吸走
that will suck the air right out of the room.
情况更糟了
It's making it worse!
巴里  听我说
Barry, listen to me.
你的手臂得转得更快
You need to move your arms faster.
我相信你  巴里
I believe in you, Barry.
罗布
Rob.
没事了  没事了
I'm okay. It's okay.
我以为要失去你了
I thought I lost you.
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen.
今晚  在火灾中
Tonight, at the fire,
你在犹豫
I saw hesitation.
质疑自己
I saw you doubting yourself.
为什么
Why is that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我猜是我害怕
Uh, I guess I was afraid
不能救出所有人
I couldn't save everyone.
好吧
Right.
巴里  如果说我们相处的这么长时间里
But if there is anything that I have learned
我从你身上发现了什么
in our time together, Barry,
那就是阻止你达成
it is that the only thing standing in the way of you
每一个你自己设定目标的障碍
achieving every goal that you set for yourself
就是你自己
is you.
你能变得多强  多快
There is no limit to how strong you will get
是没有上限的
or how fast you will go.
你所需的一切
Everything that you need,
你都有了
you already have.
谢谢你  威尔斯博士
Thank you, Dr. Wells.
你知道吗
You know,
没有你我无法完成这一切
I couldn't have done any of this without you.
没有你我也无法达成这一切
I feel the same way about you.
太奇怪了
It's so strange.
现在我看着他
I mean, I look at him now,
知道是他杀了我妈妈
and I know that he killed my mom
害我爸爸去坐牢
and he sent my dad to jail,
但是  有时候他是那么的好
but, I mean, sometimes he's just so kind
在那一刻里  我真的喜欢他
in the moment, I actually like him.
但你从来没有过
But you never did.
-没有  -没有
- No. - No.
至少我们现在知道要怎么抓住他
Well, at least now we know how to trap him.
在西斯科的梦中  他承认了所有的事
In Cisco's dream, he confessed to everything.
如果我们能重现那样的场景
If we can just recreate those conditions,
他就会再次承认
he'll do it again.
巴仔
Man, Barr.
抓坏人  逼供
Taking down bad guys, pulling confessions.
我是警察
I'm the cop.
我才是应该做这些事的人
I'm the one that's supposed to be doing this.
如果我们要让他招认
Look, if we're gonna get him to confess,
就一定要找一个他真正信任的人
it has to be with someone that he truly trusts,
一个他会真正卸下防备的人
someone that he'll genuinely let his guard down with.
他把西斯科当儿子看
He thinks of Cisco as a son.
那我们就得更好地保护他
Well, then we need to do a better job protecting him
比我保护你更好才行
than I did protecting you.
我不明白你是什么意思
I'm not sure what that means.
巴里  这都是因为我
Barry, this is all because of me.
不
No.
我就不该让威尔斯把你从医院带走
I never should've let Wells take you from that hospital.
否则的话这一切都不会发生
None of this would've ever happened.
如果你不让他带走我  我必死无疑
If you hadn't let him take me, I would be dead, for sure.
就在当时  我就觉得不对劲
But even then, I knew something wasn't right.
我的直觉告诉我不能相信他
Everything in my gut was telling me not to trust him,
但我却信了
but I did,
因为为了你平安我完全是走投无路了
because I was so desperate to see you okay.
乔  不是你的错
Joe, this isn't your fault.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
所有发生在我们身上的坏事
Look, every bad thing that has happened to us--
所有的  都是因为他
all of it-- it was him.
现在他得为此付出代价
And now he's gonna pay for it.
威尔斯设计跟一个
So, Wells set up a fake showdown
根本就不存在的对手之间的虚假对战
with a fake opponent who was never really there?
他认为如果我们看到他们俩同时出现
He figured if we saw both of them together
就能证明他不是黄衣人
it would prove that he wasn't The Man in Yellow.
一切变得越来越疯狂了
This all just keeps getting crazier and crazier.
我刚联系过威尔斯博士
I just talked to Dr. Wells.
他在市区听讲座
He's attending a lecture downtown,
五点才回来
won't be back until 5:00.
好  西斯科  在他到这时
All right, Cisco, you know when he gets here
你必须准备好这个陷阱
you need to be working on the trap
这样他就能看到你启动全息图
so he sees you set off the hologram.
等等  在你的梦里
Hold on, isn't that, in your dream,
难道不是一切都...
when everything went all...
惊悚  厄运神庙
Kali Ma. Temple of Doom.
是啊  梦里确实是那样
Yeah, that definitely happened.
但这次  我准备好对付他了
But this time, I'm ready for him.
最开始我设计这个力场
I originally designed the force field
是为了不让超速者出去
to keep a speedster from getting out.
但我已经改反了
But I've reversed it.
现在它不能让人进来
Now it won't let one in.
退后
Back up.
巴里  你没事吧
Barry, are you okay?
有用
It works.
好  只要我在里面
Okay, as long as I'm inside,
威尔斯就不能接近我
Wells won't be able to get near me.
我会在表层
And I will be in the Cortex
观看并记录所有发生的事
watching and recording everything that happens.
我们一拿到释放我爸爸
And as soon as we get the confession we need
所需的供述  我就动手
to free my dad, I'm moving in.
那我要做什么
So what do I do?
威尔斯也威胁过爱瑞丝
Wells also threatened Iris,
如果这里出了什么错
so if something goes wrong here,
我们要你看着她
we need you to keep an eye on her
直到威尔斯被控制
until Wells is neutralized.
我会一直保护爱瑞丝的  乔
I'll always keep Iris safe, Joe.
怎么了
What?
跟我来
Come here.
艾迪已经告诉我了
So, um, Eddie told me what happened,
他说你不赞成他求婚
that you kiboshed his proposal.
这本来是我和他的事
That was supposed to be between him and me.
我非常同意
I so agree with that.
而且我知道我们现在有很重要的事要处理
And I--and I know that we have a lot going on right now,
而且最不应该帮艾迪求情的人
and I should definitely be the last person
恐怕就是我  可是我不明白  乔
pleading Eddie's case, but I don't get it, Joe.
你为什么不同意
Why did you say no?
因为如果艾迪向爱瑞丝求婚了
Because if Eddie proposes to Iris,
她会被当时的浪漫气氛所打动
she's gonna get caught up in the moment and the romance,
然后说"我愿意"
and she's gonna say yes.
这有什么不好
What's wrong with that?
再次重申  我也不知道怎么会这么说
Again, I don't know why I'm saying this.
因为总有一天她会明白过来
Because one day she's gonna wake up and realize
她嫁错了人
she married the wrong guy.
可是因为她承诺过  所以她不会离婚
But she'll stay anyway because she made a promise.
我不希望她或者他
I don't want that kind of life for her.
过上那种生活
Or him.
她对你有感觉  巴里
She's got feelings for you, Barry.
或许她还不知道应该怎么应对这种感觉
She may not know how to deal with those feelings right now,
不过我了解她
but I know her.
她有这种感觉  一直有
They're there. Always have been.
这你也知道
You know that, too.
话说  爱瑞丝发短信说有紧急情况
Speaking of, Iris just sent me a 911 text.
我很快回来
I'll be right back.
我就说吧
Like I said.
怎么了
What's going on?
巴里  我知道现在不是个好时机
Look, Barry, I know it's not a good time.
可最近似乎都没有什么好时机
I mean, lately, it never seems to be a good time,
可我需要你听我说说话
but I need you to listen to me right now.
要认真听我说
Like--like, really listen to me.
当然可以
Of course. Yeah.
只要是你想说的  我都会认真听
Whatever you need to tell me, I'm listening.
好的  我知道这一开始听起来
Okay, I mean, I know this is gonna sound
会有些离谱  可是
really crazy at first, but...
中城现在所发生的一切奇怪事件
everything strange that's been going on in Central City,
都是从那晚开始的
it all goes back to that night.
也就是粒子加速器爆炸那晚
The night that the particle accelerator exploded.
我把开设博客以来  所收集到的资料
I have gone through every bit of information
全部都看了一遍
that I've collected since I started my blog--
每个爆料  传言  怪事
every tip, every rumor, every strange sighting.
所有事情都在爆炸之后才出现
Nothing predates the explosion.
无论那次爆炸向空气中释放了什么物质
Whatever was released into the atmosphere that night,
我觉得是它改变了人们
I think it changed people--
让他们有了超能力
caused them to have powers.
而且我觉得尖端科研实验室知道这件事
And I think that S.T.A.R. Labs knew about it.
我认为火人就在那工作
I think The Burning Man worked there,
而且我认为这也是闪电侠获得能力的原因
and I think that that's how The Flash got his powers too.
你怎么看
So what do you think?
我
I...
我不知道  这挺有意思
I don't know. I mean, it's--it's interesting.
是的  挺有意思
Yeah, it's interesting.
只  只是
It's--there's--there's just--
你的想法有个很大的漏洞
a big hole in your theory.
你看
You know...
我也接触了
I was affected by whatever
爆炸后释放的东西
was released by the explosion,
可是我没有任何超能力
and I don't have any powers.
-当然了  -对吧
- Obviously. - Right, yeah.
听我说  我知道这有点不太实际
Look, I mean, I know that it's-- it's really mind-blowing.
我甚至都还没跟艾迪说过这事
I mean, I haven't even talked to Eddie about it yet, but--
对了  你和艾迪  你们...
Yeah, you and Eddie-- how are...
你和艾迪之间还好吗
everything's okay with you and Eddie?
是的  当然
Sure. Sure.
我们很好  怎么了
Yeah, we're great. Why?
我  好的
I-- yeah, okay, look.
我会  让我先看看这些资料
I'm gonna--let me read over all of this stuff,
我们以后再谈这事
and we'll definitely talk about it later.
我保证  这很离谱
I promise. Just--I mean, this is crazy.
是吧  先让我看一下
Yeah, okay, just let me just go through it,
然后我们再谈  好吧
and we'll talk later, all right?
好的
Okay.
巴里
Barry.
我是爱瑞丝
It's Iris.
不知道你听不听得见我说话  希望你能
I don't know if you can hear me, but I hope you can,
因为我真的
because I really,
真的需要你醒过来
really need you to wake up.
就像那天
Like, the other day,
一个很帅的警探来吉特斯
Detective Pretty Boy came into Jitters,
然后约我出去  我就答应了
and he asked me out, and I actually said yes.
你看  你不在我就会做出这种蠢事
See, I do dumb things like that when you're not around.
而且现在家里没了你一点也不热闹
And the house is really quiet without you.
我知道你来我家住
I know that the reason that you came to live with us
是迫不得已
was awful.
可是巴里
But Barry,
你让它又有了家的感觉
you made it a home again.
你让我们又成了一家人
You made us a family again.
我们需要你
We need you.
我需要你
I need you.
你好  威尔斯博士
Hello, Dr. Wells.
讲座怎么样
How was your lecture?
无聊  沉闷
Oh, boring, tedious.
陈词滥调
Platitudinous?
比我自己说的都准确
Couldn't have said it better myself.
西斯科去哪了
Where-- where's Cisco?
他在下面
He is in the bunker.
他说他终于找出了圣诞时到底出了什么错
He thinks he finally figured out what went wrong at Christmas.
就是我们想要抓住逆闪电时
You know, when we were trying to catch The Reverse-Flash?
是的  我记得那个晚上
Yes, I remember that night.
他说他发现什么了吗
Well, did he say what he's found?
没有  只是说很重要
Nope, just that it was important.
西斯科真厉害
Good for Cisco.
好吧
Okay.
要不我下去转转
Well, maybe I'll wheel on down there,
看看他有什么进展
see what he's got.
好的
Okay.
他去了
Here he comes.
你好  西斯科
Hello, Cisco.
你挺忙啊
You've been busy.
你真是绝顶聪明  西斯科
You really are incredibly clever, Cisco.
我一直都这么说
I've always said it.
你就是他
You're him.
逆闪电
The Reverse-Flash.
一直以来乔都说得没错  对吧
Joe was right this whole time, wasn't he?
乔很厉害啊
Good Ol' Joe.
乔·韦斯特一直心存怀疑
Joe West had his doubts all along.
甚至从一开始医院那晚
Even from that first night in the hospital,
乔就知道有什么事不太对劲
Joe knew something wasn't right.
警察  他们一直都
Cops--as inconvenient now
这么讨厌
as they will be in a hundred years.
加油  西斯科  我们需要他亲口认罪
Come on, Cisco. We need a confession.
你杀了巴里的母亲
You killed Barry's mother.
我想知道原因
I want to know why.
杀死诺拉并不是我的本意
It was never my intention to kill Nora.
但从我的角度来看
But from my perspective,
她早都已经死了
she was already dead.
只是比应该的早了一些
It just happened sooner than it was supposed to.
不行  这不算认罪
No. That's not an admission.
这次你逃不掉的
You're not gonna get away with this.
我逃不掉吗
I'm not gonna get away with it?
你是聪明
Oh, you're smart.
确实聪明  西斯科
You're smart, Cisco.
不过你还不够聪明
But you're not that smart.
西斯科
Cisco!
不要
No!
他还没认罪
He didn't confess.
西斯科  你还好吗
Cisco, are you okay?
是的
Yeah.
我这辈子是再也睡不着了
I'm never ever gonna sleep ever again,
总算还好  我没事
but, yeah, I'm okay.
他死了
He's dead.
他没认罪
He didn't confess.
乔  完了
Joe, this was it.
我爸永远无法沉冤昭雪了
My dad's gonna be in prison forever.
巴里  很遗憾
Barry, I'm sorry.
搞什么
What the hell?
我以前和你说过
I told you this before.
我总是比闪电侠领先一步
I am always one step ahead... Flash.
让我再次向你介绍
Allow me to reintroduce to you
汉尼拔·贝茨先生
Mr. Hannibal Bates
以及他一经接触就能变身他人的
and his incredible ability to transform
惊人能力
into any person he touches.
我就知道那种能力迟早会派上用场
I knew that ability would come in handy.
可是没想到来得这么快
I did not expect it to come in handy this soon.
你利用了他
You used him!
正如你利用了我们所有的人
Like you used all of us!
至少他有用处
Well, he served a purpose.
轻易地就说服了他
Didn't take much convincing.
简单地承诺放他自由就搞定了
Just the simple promise of his freedom.
你毁了我的生活  我们所有人的生活
You ruined my life! All our lives!
一切事情发生后  我们支持你
We stood by you after everything that happened.
我能看出你们肯定很难理解这件事
I can see how this must be difficult for you to understand,
但是相信我
but trust me,
正是由于我为你们所做的事
your lives now are so much better
你们现在的生活才比以前更加好
because of what I have done for you.
你不必再躲了
You don't have to hide anymore.
我们知道你不是哈里森·威尔斯
We know you're not Harrison Wells.
告诉我你是谁
Just tell us who you are.
认罪是没用的
A confession will get you nowhere.
你见过我的真面目
You've seen who I am.
你知道我的能力
You know what I can do.
如果你想杀了我  动手吧
You want to kill me, go ahead.
我不会反击的
I'm not gonna fight you.
但只要告诉警察你干的好事
But just tell the police what you did.
让我爸爸沉冤昭雪
Get my dad out of prison.
我不想杀你  巴里
I don't want to kill you, Barry.
我需要你
I need you.
而且
And...
我也没预料到
I also did not anticipate,
过去15年对我而言如此艰辛
as difficult as the past 15 years have been for me,
而与你共事却这么开心
how much I would come to love working with you.
以及你们所有的人
With all of you.
但是这无法改变需要发生的事
And yet, that does not change what needs to happen.
那现在就出来面对我
Then face me now!
我们会再次面对彼此的
Oh, we will face each other again.
我向你保证  很快的
I promise you. Soon.
很快  很快的
Very, very soon.
他在时间穹顶里
He's in the Time Vault!
巴里
Barry!
这全是陷阱
It was all a set-up.
我们以为自己给他设了陷阱
We thought we set a trap for him,
可结果恰恰相反
but he set a trap for us.
天呐
Oh, my God.
爱瑞丝
Iris.
我们得找到爱瑞丝
We have to find Iris.
-为什么  -威尔斯
- Why? - Wells.
一直在监视我们每一个人
He's been watching all of us.
他在每个角落都设了监控录像
He has surveillance footage set up everywhere.
我们的家  我在警局的实验室
Our homes, my lab at the police station,
《中城新闻图报》
Central City Picture News.
西斯科  找到位置了就给我电话
Cisco, call me when you have a location.
我现在非常享受散步
I am very much enjoying this stroll.
我们需要好好散散步
We needed a good stroll.
没错
Yeah.
其实  你介意我们在这停一会吗
Actually, though, would you mind if we park here for a second?
是我爸打来的
Oh, it's my dad.
能晚点再回他电话吗
Could you call him back later?
当然
Sure.
怎么了
What's going on?
爱瑞丝  这周  当我被逮捕时
Iris, this week, when I was arrested
事情看似很糟
and it looked bad,
而你从未犹豫过
you never wavered.
你从未对我失去过信心
You never lost faith in me.
这是当然的
Impossible.
尽管如此  我们经历了一些艰难时期
And even though we've been through some rough times,
我从未对我们失去信心
I've never lost faith in us.
爱瑞丝·韦斯特
Iris West.
艾迪
Eddie?
时机不对  警探
Bad timing, Detective.
住手  离他远点
Stop! Leave him alone!
爱瑞丝  别过来
Iris, no!
我知道你的真实身份
I know who you are.
你杀了巴里的妈妈
You killed Barry's mom.
但你不必伤害任何人
But you don't have to hurt anyone else.
爱瑞丝
Hey, Iris.
没事了  是我
It's okay. It's me.
他把他带走了
He took him.
黄衣人带走了艾迪
The Man in Yellow, he took Eddie.
我保证会找到他的
I promise I will find him, okay?
发生了什么事
What is happening?
听我说  先回家
Listen to me. Go home.
别和人说起这件事
Don't say anything to anyone.
我向你发誓  我会把他带回来的
I swear to you, I will bring him back, all right?
等等  别走
Wait, stop.
巴里
Barry?
不如你摘下面具吧
You might as well take that mask off.
我知道是你  威尔斯  或者其它什么名字
I know it's you, Wells. Or whoever you really are.
容我介绍一下自己吧
Well, allow me to introduce myself.
我叫艾尔伯德
My name is Eobard.
艾尔伯德·斯旺
Eobard Thawne.
我不明白
I don't understand.
为什么你和我同姓
Why do you have my name?
为什么
Why?
因为我们是一家人  艾迪
Well, 'cause we're family, Eddie.
好笑  那家庭聚会或者婚礼上怎么没见过你
Funny, I haven't seen you at any reunions or weddings.
的确很好笑
That is funny.
原因是
And the reason for that
对这些名单上的宾客而言
is because as far as those guest lists are concerned,
我还未出生
I haven't been born yet.
所以那晚在尖端科研实验室你才没有杀我
So that's why you didn't kill me that night at S.T.A.R. Labs?
整件事
This whole thing--
一直和我有关吗
it's been about me?
不可能
Not a chance.
你  我的朋友
You, my friend,
你只是我的保险而已
are simply my insurance.
你看起来这么年轻
You look so young.
而我现在可以
And I could kill you
轻而易举地杀了你
right now so easy.
但我不会这样
What I wouldn't have given...
以前我也有过这么多机会
all those times before to have had you like this.
那么
So...
无助
helpless.
可是命运
But fate,
难以捉摸啊
it's tricky, isn't it?
我来是要毁了你
I come here to destroy you...
然后回家  我必须变成
and then to get home, I have to be the one
创造你的人
who creates you.
但我会说
But I will say,
它教育了我
it's been an education...
这些年看着你成长
Watching you grow up all these years.
科学展览和球赛
Science fairs and soccer games.
毫无迹象  毫无征兆
No hint, no sign,
毫无踪迹你将来会变成什么样的人
no trace of the man you will be one day
除了恨意  我什么也没有了
for whom I have nothing but hate.
但要说明的是
And to be clear,
没什么要原谅的
nothing is forgiven.
我会和你好好清算的
There will be a reckoning,
我向你保证
I promise you,
巴里·艾伦
Barry Allen,
你会死的
and you will die.